Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to John [Giovanni] Fabroni, Italy, Feb. 18, 1779; B F113; 13x8; Adams, Tho[ma]s, 1730-1788.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Praises De Crenis. Refers to Mazzei and Carlo Bellini.at William and Mary. Concerning Thomas Paine. Concerning the war. Refers to G. Washington.
  - Letter to Signora Teresa Fabroni, April 16, 1795; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Albany, Louise d', comtesse, 1753-1824.
    L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invites her to see some dancing.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 16, 1793; B F113; 9-1/2x7; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Mrs. Webster.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Feb. 11, 1796; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning recent publication from Bologna.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 30, 1796; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a Milanese, Melzi.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, June 1, 1797; B F113; 10x7-3/4; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Ottavio Malvezzi.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 1, 1797; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Republican form of government
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 17, 1797; B F113; 9-3/4x7; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning journals and institutes in Italy under Napoleon. Refers to Lacépède.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, July 27, 1798; B F113; 10x7-3/4; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Antoine Cagnoli and his activities.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 11, 1798; B F113; 8x7-1/2; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Local news and friendly letter.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, June 18, 1800; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Pietro Malvezzi. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, July 22, 1803; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Refers to Banks. Concerning publications which should be printed in Italy.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 17, 1803; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Dr. Nischouski, of University of Vilna, who is interested in medicine
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, April 29, 1804; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Scientific academies.
  - Letter to Signora Teresa Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 10, 1799; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning her husband and the academy.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, July 17, 1802; B F113; 9-1/2x7; Aldini, Gio[vanni], 1762-1843.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Galvanism.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, November 15, 1799; B F113; 10-1/2x7-1/2; Aldini, Giovanni, 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning natural science. Refers to Galvani and the Institute of Bologna.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, April 6, 1804; B F113; 8x6-1/4; Aldini,[Giovanni], 1762-1834.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces a Polish prince who wishes to meet famous scientists.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Alibert, [Jean Louis, baron], 1766-1837.
    Florence. A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his publications on medicine
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni., B F113; 3-1/4x3-3/4; Alibert, [Jean Louis, baron], 1766-1837.
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Hopes to see him at a mutual friend's house. Refers to Fontana.
  - Letter to Adamo fabroni, Florence, 1792; B F113; 9-1/2x7; Amoretti, C[arlo], Abbé, 1741-1816.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (See Fabroni papers.) Business of the Societá patriotica di Milano. On same sheet is: Societá Patriotica di Milano. Programma...[1792?].
  - Letter to Adamo Fabbroni, Florence, Oct. 6, 1790; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Amoretti, Carlo, [Abbé], 1741-1816.
    Milano, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Adam[o] Fabbroni, Florence, 1790; B F113; 10x7-1/4; Amoretti, Carlo, [Abbé], 1741-1816.
    Milano, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni Papers.) Geology and drilling.
  - Letter to Adam[o] Fabbroni, Florence, May 10, 1791; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Amoretti, Carlo, [Abbé], 1741-1816.
    Milano, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Recommends a man recommended by Fontana
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 27, 1801; B F113; 9x6-1/4; Amoretti, Carlo, abate, 1741-1818.
    Milan, A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni Papers.) Scientific news.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, March 11, 1808; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Anisson-Duperon, [Alexandre Jacques Laurent], 1776-1852.
    Pisa, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Hopes to return to Florence. Has met and enjoyed knowing Mazzei. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, B F113; 10x8; Anisson-Duperon, [Alexandre Jacques Laurent], 1776-1852.
    A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Will forward things to Deuchy.
  - Diploma to Abbay Pelli, May 16, 1748; B F113; 12-3/4x17-3/4; Apathistarum Academia di Florentiae.
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: G. Lanci. 1p. Seal. In Latin. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 21, 1805; B F113; 10x8; Appleton, Th[omas
    Leghorn, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Jefferson and his works, which should be translated into Italian.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 12, 1805; B F113; 10x8; Appleton, Th[omas]
    Leghorn, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Will forward pamphlet to Jefferson. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni [Fabroni], April 2, 1797; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Aroldi, Michele, 1740-1813.
    Modena, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a work for publication which he has prepared for Fabroni. Honored by Fabroni's friendship.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 24, 1797; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Aroldi, Michele, 1740-1813.
    Modena, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Explains lost letter. Cattle disease in the lowlands.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 28, 1797; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Aroldi, Michele, 1740-1813.
    Modena, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a manuscript for Fabroni. Concerning a De Vinci manuscript. Speaks of Bergolli Modanese. Cattle disease.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Jan. 26, 1798; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Aroldi, Michele, 1740-1813.
    Modena, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards chest of best bologna of Modena and hopse he enjoys it.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni] Modena, Feb. 10, 1798; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Aroldi, Michele, 1740-1813.
    A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sympathizes in his troubles. Concerning publishing Aristotle.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, April 18, 1798; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Aroldi, Michele, 1740-1813.
    Modena, A.L.S. 6p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Advises treatment for Fabroni's son and wife. Friendly letter. Concerning his own study of topography.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, May 3, 1798; B F113; 9-1/4x6-3/4; Aroldi, Michele, 1740-1813.
    Modena, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Mail has increased, so larger parcels should be sent, more infrequently. Sends certain copies of work.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 25, 1798; B F113; 9-1/4x7; Aroldi, Michele, 1740-1813.
    Modena, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards requested parcel.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, May 31, 1798; B F113; 1/4x6-3/4; Aroldi, Michele, 1740-1813.
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for publications and praises them.
  - Statement concerning Giorgio Viani, Jan. 1, 1804; B F113; 4-3/4x7-1/4; Averani, F[rancesco
    A.D.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 22, 1798; B F113; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Azara, [José Nicolas], 1731-1804.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to Paul Righini, Marseille, July 21, 1799; B F113; 8-1/2x6-3/4; Azuni, [Domenico], 1749-1829.
    Paris, 3 Thermidor an 7 A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Fabroni, identifies him, and authorizes him to carry things through customs.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, May 16, 1780; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Cannot acquire Rheum for Favi. Thanks for publications on botany. Concerning tests on air.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Jan. 16, 1792; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 3p. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Sir Georges Staunton. Refers to Wedgwood. Sheep disease. Mineralogy.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 31, 1781; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Cannot give names of seeds forwarded. Botany. Lists publications wanted. Concerning Fontana and Scheele.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Feb. 4, 1785; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Botanical news. Sends seeds. Herbarium of Linnaeus is in England.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, July 20, 1785; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for books and orders additional parts. Botany.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, July 22, 1787; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Mr. Wedgwood, son of Josiah.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 12, 1786; B F113; 9x/7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Fabroni Papers.) Believes the government shout prohibit importation of certain vegetables. Thanks for publications. Refers to Wedgwood and his thermometer.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Jan. 23, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Fabroni papers.) New plant is really new, differs from all others. Concerning his brother. Experimental medicine on hydrophobic patient Botany. Wishes another publication. Asks for description of a furnace.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, July 22, 1787; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for report on Lathyrus. Seeds from Chile. Refers to Wedgwood.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, July 1, 1789; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Leopoldo is now a member of the Royal Society of Antiquities. Botany. Thanks for books. French Revolutions is stopping scientific research.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Sept. 30, 1788; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany. Has not received books by Mr. John Wedgwood. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 22, 1789; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end, (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Mr. Johnson.
  - Letter to John [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 22, 1790; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    A.L.S. 4p.,add.,end. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for books. Concerning publications. Peale in Europe. Botany.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Aug. 18, 1792; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning scientific instruments sent his friends. Galvini's experiments in England. Volta's experiments. Electricity.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 20, 1792; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 2p. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Sir Charles Blagden.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 17, 1795; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Fabroni papers.) French Revolution has stopped philosophical research in England. Gold in Ireland Refers to Blagden. Meteorites.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 4, 1793; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    Soho Square, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Fabroni papers.] Thanks for his publication on animal electricity sent by Blagdon. Thanks for the Society of Antiquities for his works. Asks for specimen of plants.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, July 1, 1796; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart.], 1743-1820.
    A.L.S. 3p.and add., end. (see Fabroni papers.) ----Translations in Italian. 4p. Meteorites. Macropodidae.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, March 16, 1782; B F113; 9x7; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart], 1743-1820.
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany. Astronomy and Herschel.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 22, 1785; B F113; 8-3/4x7-1/2; Banks, [Sir] Jos[eph, bart], 1743-1820.
    Overton in Derbyshire, A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Fabroni papers.) Anger over disease imported from Africa to Italy in botany. Forwards seeds. Refers to the Royal society.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 8, 1790; B F113; 8-3/4x7-3/4; Barrat,
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning metals and crystals and comparisons with Fontana.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni]., B F113; 5x7; Bartolini, [Lorenzo], 1776-1850.
    A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his seal.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], June 31, July 1, 1806; B F113; 12x8-1/4; Bartolini, Biagio, 1746-1822.
    Siena, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 3, 1806; B F113; 11-3/4x8-1/2; Bartolini, Biagio, 1746-1822.
    Siena, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning their publication.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, near Haymarket, Jan. 9, 1779; B F113; 7x4-1/2; Belgioioso, [Luigi, conte di Barbiano]
    A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks favor. Refers to Sir Joseph Banks and Thunberg.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Dec. 22, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Belgioioso, Luigi, conte di Barbiano
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for books on mineralogy.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Dec. 29, 1788; B F113; 9x 7-1/4; Belgioioso, Luigi, conte di Barbiano
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for volumes on mineralogy.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, May 20, 1801; B F113; 12-1/4x8-1/2; Belleville,
    Liveorno, 30 Floreal an 9 []. L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Comments on official affairs. Refers to Gregoire.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, May 7, 1803; B F113; 10x8-1/2; Bennett, Henry Grey
    London, A.L.S. 5p.and add. In French and English. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the names, Pele, Pelle, Pella, and Pal, and possible locations, from ancient sources.
  - Letter to J[ean] Fabroni, Florence, July 4, 1807; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Berard & Martin & cie.
    Montpellier, L. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Will ship goods at the first opportunity.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 1, 1807; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Berard et Martin & cie.
    Montpellier, L. 1p.and add.,end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the shipment of his order.
  - Letter to J[ean] Fabroni, Florence, March 1, 1808; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Berard et Martin.
    Montpelier, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.with letter of 2p.in handwriting.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him of new name of the company Shipment of sulphuric acids.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni,Florence, Jan. 25, 1802; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Tartaric acid.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 10, 1806; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the shipping of orders.
  - Letter to J[Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 29, 1806; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 5p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Acids. Cannot furnish him with nitric acid. Sulphuric acids. Ether.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Oct. 22, 1816; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2 and 4x6; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 3p.and add.and enc.of 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Will ship him the acids. Regrets he cannot furnish nitric acid.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, June 2, 1817; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2, 4x6; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 3p.and add.and enc.of 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the making and shipping of various acids. Hopes to sell him nitric acid.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni,Florence, Sept. 4, 1819; B F113; 10x8; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him of changes in price of wine and nitric acid.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Nov. 18, 1819; B F113; 10x8; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards packages containing nitric acid, ect. Botany.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb.2, 1820; B F113; 10x8; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Shipments of nitric acid and payment for them. Botany.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 15, 1820; B F113; 10x8; Berard, E
    Montpellier, L. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him of a shipment and of the price of it.
  - Letter to J[ea]n Fabbroni,Florence, July 22, 1820; B F113; 10x8; Berard, E
    Montpellier, L. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany. Work at the Paris mint.
  - Letter to Jean Fabbroni, Florence, Sept. 14, 1820; B F113; 10x7-3/4, 2-3/4x5; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 3p.and add.with 2p.enc. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him of shipment and when it may be delivered.
  - Letter to J[ean] Fabroni, Florence, March 24, 1821; B F113; 10x8; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Events have prevented his purchasing cypress trees(?).
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Jan. 25, 1823; B F113; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Can furnish all the nitric acid he will need, in the event of war. Botany.
  - Letter to [Silvestro Grilly], Florence, July 22, 1816; B F113; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Berard, E
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 2p.and add. End.by. G.Fabroni(?) In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the making of nitric acid, in Italy, and the possibility of shipping it to him from France.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 28, 1807; B F113; 11-3/4x8-1/2; Bernard,
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Wishes him well. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 18, 1807; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Are busy with the war and cannot visit. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 25, 1807; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Will visit him and wants him to know that no one believes the lies about him.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, October 2, 1807; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Says that General Clarke still regards him highly and doesn't believe any of the accusations.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, October 6, 1807; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Bernard,
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Reassures him of General Clarke's high regard and affection.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Oct. 16, 1807; B F113; 8-1/2x6; Bernard,
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Tells him not to worry, that General Clarke is doing all he can. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Oct. 28, 1807; B F113; 10x8; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) States that his friends are working for him [Fabroni]. Napoleon's plans for travel.
  - Letter to J[ean] Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 9, 1807; B F113; 8-1/2x6; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him of difficulties in sending things by post.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 16, 1807; B F113; 8-1/2x6; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Business and shipments.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 23, 1807; B F113; 10x8; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Plans for a trip. Route of Napoleon.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 21, 1807; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/4; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Delighted everything is all right. Sorry to hear of the illness of his wife.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 28, 1807; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/4; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Delighted his wife is better. Asks for shipment of some bottles [of wine?].
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 30, 1807; B F113; 7-1/2x5; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks that he purchase a straw hat and send it to Venice of General Clarke.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Jan. 4, 1808; B F113; 8-1/2x6; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. in French. (see Fabroni papers.) Inquires about his wife. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Jan. 18, 1808; B F113; 10x8; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends information from General Clarke. Is glad Signora Fabroni is better.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Jan. 20, 1808; B F113; 10x8; Bernard,
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Directions for forwarding a parcel for General Clarke. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Jan. 26, 1808; B F113; 10-1/4x7-1/4; Bernard,
    Perruggia, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks him for his kindnesses.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Feb. 26, 1808; B F113; 10x8; Bernard,
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Describes Rome. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, June 27, 1793; B F113; 8-3/4x7; Bicchierai, Alessandro, 1734-1797.